Pearl a dynamic interpreted scripting language famous for its powerful text
Pearl 是一种动态解释脚本语言，以其强大的文本
processing abilities it was developed in 1987 by Larry wall a linguist who
处理能力而闻名，它是由语言学家 Larry wall 于 1987 年开发的，当有人说 Pearl 他们通常谈论版本 5 时，他将其
designed it to feel more like a human language than a computer language when
设计为更像人类语言而不是计算机语言
someone says Pearl they're usually talking about version 5. there was a
。 有一个
version 6 under development but it evolved into another language called
版本 6 正在开发中，但它演变成另一种称为
Raku Pearl is often referred to as a glue language and has been dubbed the
Raku Pearl 的语言，通常被称为胶水语言，被称为
Swiss Army chainsaw of the Internet it's most commonly used to write CGI scripts
Internet 的瑞士军电锯，它最常用于
that allow web servers to communicate with external programs its powerful
编写允许 Web 服务器与之通信的 CGI 脚本 外部程序 其强大的
string parsing abilities has made it the language of choice on high traffic sites
字符串解析能力使其成为
like DuckDuckGo booking.com and Craigslist syntactically it resembles C
DuckDuckGo booking.com 和Craigslist 等高流量网站的首选语言 在语法上它类似于 C
but is far more compressed allowing developers to write very tourist code
但压缩得多，允许开发人员编写非常旅游代码，
like one-liners that hack together a solution much quicker than other
如将解决方案组合在一起的单行代码比
scripting languages like python it contains a large collection of language
Python 等其他脚本语言快得多，它包含大量语言
Primitives and a ton of shortcuts for getting things done quickly you may find
原语和大量快速完成工作的快捷方式你可能会觉得
it ugly and awkward but system administrators love it because it gets
它丑陋和尴尬，但系统管理员喜欢它，因为它
the job done to get started install the Pearl interpreter then create a file
完成了开始安装Pearl 解释器的工作，然后创建一个
ending in.pl it's a scripting language so we start with a shebang and point it
以.pl 结尾的文件，它是一种脚本语言，所以我们 从 shebang 开始并将其
to the interpreter's binary declare a variable with a dollar sign then print
指向解释器的二进制文件 声明一个带有美元符号的变量，然后将其
it to the standard output and the variable can be easily interpolated into
打印到标准输出，该变量可以很容易地插入
another string variables can be scoped locally with the my keyword or globally
另一个字符串变量可以使用 my 关键字在本地或全局
to an entire package with the hour keyword the dollar sign creates a scalar
到整个包 使用 hour关键字，美元符号创建一个标量
variable which is a single value like a string or number if we change the dollar
变量，它是一个单一的值，如字符串或数字，如果我们将美元
sign to the at symbol this variable becomes an array the index of any item
符号更改为 at 符号，此变量将成为一个数组，现在可以使用括号访问数组中任何项目的索引
in the array can be accessed with brackets now name the variable with a
用百分号命名变量
percent sign to get a hash or key value pair to access one of its Keys use
以获得散列或键值对以访问其中一个键使用
braces one of the design principles of pearl is things that are different
大括号珍珠的设计原则之一是 不同
should look different handle conditional logic using IF or unless then make it
应该看起来不同使用 IF 处理条件逻辑，或者除非然后通过将其
more concise by refactoring it to one line then make it even more concise
重构为一行使其更简洁，然后
using the ternary operator one of the most unusual things about Pearl is that
使用三元运算符使其更简洁Pearl 最不寻常的事情之一是
your functions are defined as subroutines instead of defining
您的函数被定义为子例程
parameters within parentheses like most other languages any arguments passed to
像大多数其他语言一样，在括号内定义参数 任何传递
the function can be accessed with the at underscore array when it comes to
给函数的参数都可以在解析文本时使用下划线数组访问
parsing text regex is built in and The Binding operator can easily match a
内置正则表达式，并且绑定运算符可以轻松地将
string to a regular expression Pearl also has a lot of magic features like
字符串与正则表达式匹配 很多神奇的功能，比如
Auto vivification where if we try to increment a value in an array that
自动激活，如果我们尝试在一个不存在的数组中增加一个值，
doesn't exist it will automatically bring to life all the elements in
它会自动使现在之间的所有元素恢复活力，
between now to render code open the terminal and run The Interpreter this
以呈现代码打开终端并运行解释器，这
has been Pearl in 100 seconds hit the like button and subscribe if you want to
已经是珍珠 100秒点击喜欢按钮并订阅如果你
see more short videos like this thanks for watching and I will see you in the
想看到更多这样的短片谢谢观看，我会看到 你
next one
在下一个